Welcome to the “Living in Science” Online Course.
I am Dmitry Malkov, director of Science Communication Centre
and lecturer at ITMO University.
In the following two videos, I will discuss
the focus of our course and how it is organized.
I will inform you on the key modules,
lecturers and requirements. Most importantly,
you will be able to answer the question:
Which forms of life exist in science?
Every student ponders about
his or her place in science.
During the study period at University,
students undertake
the role of a researcher to discover
his or her own scientific interests.
Each of these interests require
countless hours in the laboratory,
making it difficult to research each one.
We can conclude that the field
of science is connected with
countless experiments, hardware setups,
and complex calculations.
However, the field is not limited
to this.
Science can be seen as
a social institution.
The role science and technology
has taken in the fields
of economic and social development
has always been a subject matter
for scholars and thinkers.
Vannevar Bush, an American scientist
and public figure,
had a prominent impact on the
modern perspective of science
in the 20th century.
He was able to convince Presidents
Franklin D. Roosevelt and Harry S. Truman
of the need to control technology during war
and facilitate peace post-war.
Bush always said that science is
a “goose that lays golden eggs”.
That is to say science and technology
gave rise to economic
and social prosperity.
His point of view was later confirmed through
the works of many economists,
including Nobel laureate Robert Solow.
Not surprisingly, fundamental and applied research
is now embedded in our reality, from the methods
of communication and transportation
to the interactions within ecology
and the health care system.
The idea of prosperity has surpassed
a goose laying golden eggs
to geese laying golden eggs.
This state of affairs requires
modern scientists
to be more proactive and have the
capability to convey their ideas to
a variety of audiences: the state,
the funding organizations
and the industry representatives.
The illusion of a scientist working alone
in the dark has no validity
in modern science.
Today the boundaries of scientific
disciplines are being redefined
before one’s eyes.
Interdisciplinarity
and transdisiciplinarity approaches
have allowed scientists to continuously
go beyond their scientific fields to collaborate
in search of solutions.
To be successful in science today,
your expertise
and research skills need
to be complemented by
a range of soft skills.
Not only should you be up to date
in your research field, but also understand
the national priorities for scientific
and technical development.
You will need to be exposed to global challenges,
build a research strategy and
a commercialization model
for your developments.
You will then be able to communicate
your ideas to grantors,
business representatives and government officials.
We hope that this course will
help you to find
your way in science!